Bradley Allen

Port Arthur, TX 77642 (409) 365-9024

allenbradley91@hotmail.com

bradleydallen.com

Summary Skills

Exceptionally driven and dependable technical problem solver with a customer service record and superb work ethic. Highly proficient in understanding technical problems and producing a clear, concise, and understandable solution.

- Excellent grasp of and experience with low-level programming languages Java, C, and C++.
- Full knowledge of web design and structure including the MERN stack and the framework implementation during web development.
- Sound familiarity with using Windows, Linux, and MacOS operating systems.

Languages: C, C++, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Shell, HTML5, CSS

Technologies: React. is, Next. is, Express. is, MongoDB, Tailwind CSS, MySQL, Bash, Git, AWS,

Projects

Portfolio Website

| 04/2022 to 06/2022

- A personal website portfolio to showcase projects, and act as a business card.
- Implemented the MERN stack, which includes MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.

Experience

EDF Trading North America | SCADA Engineer

| 01/2024 to Present

- Implemented and maintained SCADA system, ensuring continuous monitoring and control of data.
- Development of C/C++ programs for low-level database manipulation using pointers.
- Configured routers using various networking protocols such as DNP, Modbus, TCP/IP.
- Successfully established and configured RTU registers for accurate dataflow.
- Participated in rotational 24/7 on-call support to resolve issues and maintain software uptime.

Amazon | Software Development Engineer Intern

| 05/2023 to 07/2023

- Project based internship to develop, maintain, and learn best practices in software development.
- Developed customer based software by deploying infrastructure as code (IaC) using AWS CDK.
- Participated in the Agile development cycle, and learned and developed using Amazon Web Services.
- Solved a critical problem that improved the workflow and maintenance of production software.

Education

Lamar University – Beaumont, TX | Bachelor of Science

Computer Science 10/2020 to 12/2023